Guide to the Larry McMurtry Papers
University of Houston Libraries
Larry McMurtry Papers
1955-1986
03/1970-006
McMurtry, Larry
29.00 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
The Larry McMurtry Collection contains multiple typescript manuscript drafts of the novels Leaving Cheyenne, The Last Picture Show, Moving On, Somebody's Darling, Cadillac Jack: A Novel, The Desert Rose, Lonesome Dove, and Texasville, plus manuscript notes and publisher's copies related to some of these works. The collection also contains the typescript manuscripts and first galley proofs for the book of essays In a Narrow Grave.
Biographical Information:
Larry McMurtry is probably the most well-known writer to have emerged from Texas in the twentieth century, appealing to both critics and readers with his novels of the contemporary and historic American West. His trail-drive saga Lonesome Dove earned McMurtry the Pulitzer Prize for fiction in 1986, and many of his books have become national bestsellers. Lonesome Dove was turned into a highly-acclaimed television mini-series, and several of his novels have been made into films, most notably The Last Picture Show, which garnered McMurtry an Academy Award nomination for the screenplay, and Terms of Endearment.
Larry McMurtry was born in 1936, and grew up in Archer City, Texas, the son and the grandson of cattle ranchers. He completed his undergraduate studies at the North Texas State University, and received his M.A. in English from Rice University in 1960.
In 1961 he released his first novel, Horseman, Pass By. That novel and the two which followed, Leaving Cheyenne (1963) and The Last Picture Show (1966), were set in the imaginary town of Thalia, and explored small town life and the changes taking place in the rural West. Between 1963 and 1969, McMurtry also taught creative writing at Rice University.
In 1969 McMurtry moved to Washington D.C., where he became co-owner and operator of a rare book store called Booked Up. While living in Washington, he wrote three novels about turbulent relationships that were primarily set in Houston – Moving On (1970), All My Friends Are Going to Be Strangers (1972), and Terms of Endearment (1975). His next three novels are generally considered less successful, transitional novels.
1986’s Lonesome Dove was a departure for McMurtry, a rambling story set in the West of the 1870s. Since writing Lonesome Dove, he has been equally prolific in two types of book – contemporary novels such as Texasville (1987) and Evening Star (1992) which revisit characters from earlier works, and historically based novels like Anything for Billy (1988) and Buffalo Girls (1990) which tell the stories of legendary figures such as Billy the Kid and Calamity Jane. McMurtry has also released three more novels featuring characters from Lonesome Dove, the 1993 sequel Streets of Laredo, the 1996 prequel Dead Man’s Walk, and the 1997 prequel Comanche Moon. Like Lonesome Dove, these novels were made into television mini-series.
McMurtry has continued to write novels, with the latest from the Last Picture Show series, Rhino Ranch, being released in 2009. In 2005, McMurtry won the Academy Award for his screenplay of the movie Brokeback Mountain, which he co-wrote with Diana Ossana.
In addition to novels, McMurtry has also published books of essays, film criticism, short stories, and several volumes of memoirs. He has one son, James Lawrence, and currently lives in Archer City, Texas, where he owns a rare book store.
Access Terms
This Collection is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Genre/Form of Material:
Correspondence; Novels; Photographs; Screenplays; Short stories; Typescripts
Personal Name:
McMurtry, Larry
Topical Term:
Authors -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century; Fiction, American; Motion picture plays, American; Short stories, American
Acquisition Information:
A large portion of the collection, which included typescripts, essays and screenplays, was purchased in 1985. Other materials in the collection were acquired starting in the mid-1960s and continuing through 1986, and were acquired from a variety of sources. For more information, please contact the collection curator.
Conditions Governing Access:
Open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Larry McMurtry Collection contains multiple typescript manuscript drafts of the novels Leaving Cheyenne, The Last Picture Show, Moving On, Somebody's Darling, Cadillac Jack: A Novel, The Desert Rose, Lonesome Dove, and Texasville, plus manuscript notes and publisher's copies related to some of these works. The collection also contains the typescript manuscripts and first galley proofs for the book of essays In a Narrow Grave.
The McMurtry Collection includes a screenplay for Hud (the film adaptation of McMurtry's Horseman, Pass By), and the screenplay for the John Cougar Mellencamp film project Falling from Grace (titled Ridin' the Cage and Indiana Moon in these drafts). Also in the collection are scripts for the cable television movies Montana and Memphis (titled September, September in these drafts), which was adapted from a novel by Shelby Foote and co-written with Cybil Shepherd. Many scripts are included which have not been produced, such as Cantrell and Somebody's Darling, which credits Diane Keaton as co-writer in some drafts.
The collection includes a large amount of correspondence. There are three major sections of correspondence – from McMurtry to his friend and Bookman store owner Grace David, from McMurtry to his friend Mike Kunkel, and from Harper and Row editor John Leggett to McMurtry. The Leggett correspondence concerns changes to the manuscripts for Horseman, Pass By and Leaving Cheyenne. Other correspondence includes that from McMurtry to book dealer Miles Karpilow.
A wide-ranging collection, the Larry McMurtry Collection also includes short prose and poetry, numerous literary reviews written by McMurtry, news articles about his books and films, notes on projects considered, transcriptions of taped interviews used as research for The Desert Rose, scripts which McMurtry worked on as an advisor without receiving credit, photographs, and other miscellaneous documents.
The collection is organized into six major series: McMurtry’s Writings, Correspondence, Other Projects, Works by Other Authors, Photographs and Miscellaneous. The first series, McMurtry’s Writings, contains the bulk of the collection contents. This series is divided into three sub-series: Novels, Scripts and Other Writings. Most individual works are given their own sub-series, and these are arranged alphabetically. The Correspondence, Other Projects, and Miscellaneous series have also been subdivided.
Additional manuscript material of Larry McMurtry is held at the University of North Texas in Denton, Southwest Texas State University in San Marcos, and Rice University in Houston. The Texana Collection of the Willis Library at the University of North Texas contains some of McMurtry's student literary submissions and papers, plus typescript manuscripts of Horseman, Pass By and Leaving Cheyenne. The Southwestern Writers Collection at the Alkek Library of Southwest Texas State University includes the screenplay and many other materials from the television mini-series Lonesome Dove, and a typescript of the 1972 screenplay Streets of Laredo, on which the Lonesome Dove novel was based. The Woodson Research Center of Fondren Library at Rice University has two collections of papers documenting McMurtry’s collaboration with Diana Ossana. These collections contain drafts, correspondence, and related materials.
Detailed List of Contents
- McMurtry's Writings
  This bulk of this series consists of typescripts, notes, and research for McMurtry’s writings. Issues of American Film magazine which contain McMurtry’s essays on film that were later compiled into the book Film Flam have been separated from the collection and cataloged.
  - Novels
    - Cadillac Jack
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter I-VIII; Outline; Notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
        Typescript draft, with corrections
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter IX-XV; Book II, Chapter I-II (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter III-IX (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter X-XV (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - First draft: Book III, Chapter I-VII (Box 1, Folder 5)
      - First draft: Book III, Chapter VIII-XIV (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - First draft: Book III, Chapter XV; Book IV, Chapter I-II (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - First draft: Book IV, Chapter III-VII (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - First draft: Book IV, Chapter VIII-XI (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Notes and suggested cuts (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Second draft: Book I, Chapter I-XIII, XIV(?), XV (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Second draft: Book III, Chapter X-XIII (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Second draft: Book III, Chapter XIV-XV; Book IV, Chapter I-IV (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Second draft: Book IV, Chapter V-X (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Second draft: Book IV, Chapter XI-XV (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - Second draft: Book IV, Chapter XVI-XVIII (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - Preface, first and second drafts (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - Third draft: Book II, Chapter IV-XV; Book III, Chapter I (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Third draft: Book III, Chapter II-XV (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Third draft: Book III, Chapter XVI; Book IV, Chapter I-IX (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - Third draft: Book IV, Chapter X-XV; Book V, Chapter I-III (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Third draft: Book V, Chapter IV-XII (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - Third draft: Book V, Chapter XIII-XVIII (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - Third draft: Book I, Chapter I-XIII; Book II, Chapter I-III (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - Third draft: i-iii; Book I, Chapter I-XV (Box 2, Folder 1)
        Photocopied typescript, with corrections
      - Third draft: Book II, Chapter I-XIV (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Third draft: Book II, Chapter XV; Book III, Chapter I-XIII (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Third draft: Book III, Chapter XIV-XVI; Book IV, Chapter I-VII (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Third draft: Book IV, Chapter VIII-XV (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - Third draft: Book V, Chapter I-X (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Third draft: Book V, Chapter XI-XVIII (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Fourth draft: Book I, Chapter I-XIV; Book II, Chapter V (Box 2, Folder 8)
        Typescript draft
      - Fourth draft: Book II, Chapter VI-XV; Book II, Chapter I-IV (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - Fourth draft: Book III, Chapter V-XVI; Book IV, Chapter I-II (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - Fourth draft: Book IV, Chapter III-XII (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - Fourth draft: Book IV, Chapter XIII-XV; Book V, Chapter I-VII (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - Fourth draft: Book V, Chapter VIII-XV (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - Fourth draft: Book V, Chapter XVI-XVIII (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - Publisher's Copy: Book I, Chapter I-XVI; Book II, Chapter I-V; Publisher letter; Memo (Box 2, Folder 15)
        Copyedited typescript, with publisher's note; memo; front matter
      - Publisher's Copy: Book II, Chapter VI-XV; Book III, Chapter IV (Box 2, Folder 16)
        Copyedited typescript
      - Publisher's Copy: Book III, Chapter V-XVI (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - Publisher's Copy: Book IV, Chapter I-X (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - Publisher's Copy: Book IV, Chapter XI-XV; Book V, Chapter I-IV (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - Publisher's Copy: Book V, Chapter V-XIII (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - Publisher's Copy: Book V, Chapter XIV-XVIII (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Desert Rose
      - Interview transcript: James Maxwell (Box 3, Folder 1)
        Photocopied typescript
      - Interview transcript: Lydia Farrington (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - Interview transcript: Grandma Thompson (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Interview transcript: Lucy Toto (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Interview transcript: Heidi Page (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - Interview transcript: Dan Parker (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - Interview transcript: Briony Merriman (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Interview transcript: Robin Nairn (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Interview transcript: Joy Plutte (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - Interview transcript: Linda Hahn (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - Transcript: Backstage Elk at Bravo Vegas (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - Interview transcript: Morag Veljkovic (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - Interview transcript: Eddie Ball and Danny (?) (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Interview transcript: Joanna Courey (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - Interview transcript: Lilly Silverstone (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - Interview transcript: Donald Carns (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - Interview transcript: Donald Carns and Jan Benare (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - Interview transcript: Jan Benare (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - Interview transcript: Maude Fox (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - Interview transcript: Muffy McQuiddy (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - Interview transcript: Sharon Shakelford (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - Interview transcript: Janet Ford (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - Interview transcript: Felicia Atkins (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Interview transcript: Michel Stany (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - Interview transcript: Lisa Browder (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - Interview transcript: Fiona Kelly (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - Interview transcript: Nikki Adamo (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - Interview transcript: Jim Reid (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - Interview transcript: Morgan Hildebrand (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - Interview transcript: Alan Hadley (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - Interview transcript: [Matt?] Gregory (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - Interview transcript: Rosemarie Tall (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - Interview transcript: Eddie Ball (1) (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - Interview transcript: Eddie Ball (2) (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - Interview transcript: Eddie Ball (3) (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - Background material: Casino show programs (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - Feathers by Teresa Carpenter, with notes by McMurtry (Box 3, Folder 37)
        Photocopied typescript, with notes
      - Master's thesis on Las Vegas dancers, by Alan Hadley (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - First draft: Preface; Second draft: Preface (Box 3, Folder 39)
        Typescript, with corrections
      - First draft: Part I-II, through page 101 (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - First draft: Part III (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - First draft: Part IV (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - First draft: Part V (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - Second draft: Portions used in readings (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - Second draft: Portions used in readings (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Second draft: Portions not used in readings (Box 4, Folder 5)
        Transcript, with corrections
      - Second draft: Portions not used in readings (Box 4, Folder 6)
      - Second draft: Portions not used in readings (Box 4, Folder 7)
      - Printer's proof: Part I; Letter (Box 4, Folder 8)
      - Printer's proof: Part I-IV (Box 4, Folder 9)
      - Printer's proof: Part V-VII (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - The Last Picture Show
      - Letter; Character list; Outline (Box 4, Folder 11)
        Typescript; Manuscript notes
      - There Will be Peace in Korea, first draft (Box 4, Folder 12)
        Typescript, with corrections and note
      - There Will be Peace in Korea, second draft (Box 4, Folder 13)
      - First draft: Book I, Title page, Chapter I-IV (Box 4, Folder 14)
        Typescript, with note, signed
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter V-IX (Box 4, Folder 15)
        Typescript
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter X; Book II, Chapter I-II (Box 4, Folder 16)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter III-V (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter VI-IX (Box 4, Folder 18)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter X-XV (Box 4, Folder 19)
      - Discarded pages (Box 4, Folder 20)
      - First draft: Title page; Book I, Chapter I-IV (Box 4, Folder 21)
        Typescript (carbon), with note
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter V-VIII (Box 4, Folder 22)
        Typescript (carbon)
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter IX-X; Book II, Chapter I (Box 4, Folder 23)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter II-IV (Box 4, Folder 24)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter V-VIII (Box 4, Folder 25)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter IX-XIII (Box 4, Folder 26)
      - First draft: Book II, Chapter XIV-XVI (Box 4, Folder 27)
      - Agent's copy: Chapter I-V (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Agent's copy: Chapter VI-IX (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - Agent's copy: Chapter X-XIII (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Agent's copy: Chapter XIV-XVIII (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Agent's copy: Chapter XIX-XXII (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Agent's copy: Chapter XXIII-XXV (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - Second draft: i-ii; Chapter I-V (Box 5, Folder 7)
        Carbon typescript, with corrections
      - Second draft: Chapter VI-IX (Box 5, Folder 8)
      - Second draft: Chapter X-XIII (Box 5, Folder 9)
      - Second draft: Chapter XIV-XVIII (Box 5, Folder 10)
      - Second draft: Chapter XIX-XXV (Box 5, Folder 11)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter I-VI (Box 5, Folder 12)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter VII-X (Box 5, Folder 13)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XI-XV (Box 5, Folder 14)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XVI-XX (Box 5, Folder 15)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XXI-XXVI (Box 5, Folder 16)
      - Publisher's copy: Discarded pages (Box 5, Folder 17)
      - Dust jacket (Box 5, Folder 18)
      - Promotional material - Bookmark (?) (Box 5, Folder 19)
      - Excerpt in Janus (Box 5, Folder 20)
        Full publication
      - Excerpt in The Thresher Review (Box 5, Folder 21)
      - Reviews and articles (Box 5, Folder 22)
      - Reviews and articles (Box 5, Folder 23)
      - Review and interview in Collage (Box 5, Folder 24)
      - Articles about film version (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Leaving Cheyenne
      - Notes and outline in stenographer's notebook (Box 5, Folder 26)
      - Early fragments: Part I, Chapter 1; Part II, Chapter 1-6; Part III, Chapter 1-2, 5 (Box 5, Folder 27)
        Typescript(some carbon), with corrections
      - Early draft as Los Companyeros: Part [I or III], Chapter I; Part II, Chapter I-VI (Box 5, Folder 28)
      - Early draft as Los Companyeros: Part III, Chapter I-V; Part IV, I-III (Box 5, Folder 29)
      - Memories of the Old Tribe Draft: Chapter I-IV (Box 5, Folder 30)
      - Memories of the Old Tribe Draft: Chapter V-IX (Box 5, Folder 31)
      - Draft: Book I, Chapter I-7, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 32)
        Typescript, with note
      - Draft: Book I, Chapter 8-20, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      - Draft: Book I, Chapter 21-24, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - Draft: Book II, Chapter 1-9, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Draft: Book I, Chapter 1-10, February 1963 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Draft: Book I, Chapter 11-24, February 1963 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Draft: Book II, Chapter 1-9, February 1963 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Draft: Book III, Chapter 1-9, February 1963 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Reviews and articles (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Galley proof (Box 27, Item 2)
    - Lonesome Dove
      - Notes and outline, handwritten (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Synopsis (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Synopsis, corrected (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 37, returned from J.R. Hall (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - First draft: Front material; Chapter I-IV (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - First draft: Book I, Chapter V-VII (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - First draft: Chapter VIII-X (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - First draft: Chapter XI-XIII (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - First draft: Chapter XIV-XVIII (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - First draft: Chapter XIX-XXIII (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - First draft: Chapter XXIV-XXX (Box 6, Folder 18)
      - First draft: Chapter XXXI-37 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - First draft: Chapter 38-43 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - First draft: Chapter 44-47 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - First draft: Chapter 48-51 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - First draft: Chapter 52-55 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - First draft: Chapter 56-61 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - First draft: Chapter 62-67 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - First draft: Chapter 68-72 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - First draft: Chapter 73-74 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      - First draft: Book IV, Chapter 75-80 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      - First draft: Chapter 81-84 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      - First draft: Chapter 85-87 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      - First draft: Chapter 88-91 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      - First draft: Chapter 92-94 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      - First draft: Chapter 95-100 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      - First draft: Chapter 82-85 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      - First draft: Chapter 86-89 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      - First draft: Chapter 90-92 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - First draft: Chapter 93-97 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      - Second draft: Front material; Chapter I-IV (Box 7, Folder 9)
      - Second draft: Chapter VI-X (Box 7, Folder 10)
      - Second draft: Chapter XI-XVI (Box 7, Folder 11)
      - Second draft: Chapter XVII-XXV (Box 7, Folder 12)
      - Second draft: Chapter XXVI-XXXIV (Box 7, Folder 13)
      - Second draft: Chapter XXXV-XLII (Box 7, Folder 14)
      - Second draft: Chapter XLIII-XLVIII (Box 7, Folder 15)
      - Second draft: Chapter XLIX-LV (Box 7, Folder 16)
      - Second draft: Chapter LVI-LXIV (Box 7, Folder 17)
      - Second draft: Chapter LXV-LXX (Box 7, Folder 18)
      - Second draft: Chapter LXXI-LXXIV (Box 7, Folder 19)
      - Second draft: Book III, Chapter LXXI-LXXIV (Box 7, Folder 20)
      - Second draft: Chapter LXXXI-LXXXVI (Box 7, Folder 21)
      - Second draft: Chapter LXXXVII-XC (Box 7, Folder 22)
      - Second draft: Chapter XIC-XVC (Box 7, Folder 23)
      - Second draft: Chapter XVIC-CII (Box 7, Folder 24)
      - Publisher's copy: Front matter: Chapter I-V (Box 8, Folder 1)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter VI-X (Box 8, Folder 2)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XI-XVI (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XVII-XXV (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Publisher's copy: Part II, Chapter XXVI-XXXIV (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XXXV-XLII (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XLIII-XLVIII (Box 8, Folder 7)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XLIX-LV (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter LVI-LXIII (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter LXIV-LXX (Box 8, Folder 10)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter LXXI-LXXIV (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Publisher's copy: Book III(?), Chapter LXXV-LXXX (Box 8, Folder 12)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter LXXXI-LXXXVII (Box 8, Folder 13)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter LXXXVIII-XIIC (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XIIIC-XVIIC (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Publisher's copy: Chapter XVIIIC-CII (Box 8, Folder 16)
      - Photocopied typescript: Pages returned from Columbia Pictures (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Moving On
      - Manuscript notes in Big Chief Tablet (Box 8, Folder 18)
      - The Water and the Blood, First draft: Chapters I-II, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 19)
      - The Water and the Blood, First draft: Chapters III-IV, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 20)
      - The Water and the Blood, First draft: Chapters V-X, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - The Water and the Blood, First draft: misc. pages, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 22)
        Typescript (some carbon), with corrections
      - Lovebreaking, Second draft: Book I, Chapters I-II (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Lovebreaking, Second draft: Book I, Chapter ? (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - Lovebreaking, Second draft: Book II, Chapter I-? (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Lovebreaking, Second draft: Book II, Chapter ?, Insert 1-9, Chapter 2, Uncle Jay (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Lovebreaking, Second draft: Book III (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Lovebreaking, Third draft: Book I, Chapter I-V (Box 9, Folder 4)
        Typescript, with corrections and notes
      - Lovebreaking, Third draft: Book I, Chapter VI-VIII, Book II, Chapter I-II (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Lovebreaking, Third draft: Book II, Chapter III-VII (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Lovebreaking, Third draft: Book II, Chapter VIII-XIII (Box 9, Folder 7)